

School of Mathematics and Physics, The University of Queensland

■ daniel@vfryer.com | 😭 danielvfryer.com | 🖸 frycast | 💆 _frycast

I'm in love with statistics, programming and science, but the four of us have complicated relationship issues. Complex data analyses are used in every industry and scientific field, but so many of the results are unintuitive and difficult to interpret. I aim to make complex models more transparent, understandable and explainable. To make this research accessible, I write software packages and libraries in R, Python and Julia. My aim is not just to work theoretically, but also to apply these methods to impactful real world problems. Aside from research, I'm a passionate teacher, and I serve as a council member and Early Career and Student Statisticians' Representative at the Statistical Society of

Education

The University of Queensland

Saint Lucia, QLD, AU

PhD | Statistics and Mathematics

2019-Current

• Explaining, exploring and clustering with non-linear and complex data

La Trobe University Melbourne, VIC, AU

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE | MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS WITH FIRST CLASS HONOURS (WEIGHTED AVERAGE MARK: 97)

Random fields: Long memory, and R for cosmology

2014-2018

Experience ____

Monash University Melbourne, Victoria, AU

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

2020-Current

2020-Current

• Politics & International Relations

University of Auckland

The University of Queensland

Saint Lucia, QLD, AU

CASUAL INSTRUCTOR | DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

• Master's of Data Science project support

Auckland, Auckland Region, NZ

COURSE INSTRUCTOR | NEW ZEALAND SOCIAL STATISTICS NETWORK

2018-Current

• Introduction to SQL for academics and professionals

La Trobe University Melbourne, VIC, AU

SESSIONAL LECTURER | DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS AND STATISTICS

2018-Current

• Master's level meta-analysis | Master's level database fundamentals

The University of Queensland Saint Lucia, QLD, AU

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2019-2019

• Digital phenotyping for transdiagnostic clustering and psychiatric prognosis

La Trobe University Melbourne, VIC, AU

RESEARCH SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | DEPARTMENT OF MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2018-2019

· Spherical data analysis in R on the HEALPix grid

Service_

Statistical Society of Australia Melbourne, VIC, AU

COUNCIL MEMBER | EARLY CAREER AND STUDENT STATISTICIANS' REPRESENTATIVE

2020-Current

Dimension Reduction and Meta Analysis Research Group

Melbourne, VIC, AU

MEMBER | WEBSITE MAINTAINER

2017-Current Melbourne, VIC, AU

SENIOR MENTOR AND FOUNDING MEMBER

2017-2019

Research School on Statistics and Data Science

Melbourne, VIC, AU 2019-2019

PEER REVIEWER (3 ARTICLES)

DECEMBER 2020

Campus Consultancy

Journal of Open Source Software	Melbourne, VIC, AU
Peer Reviewer (1 article)	2019–2019
Victorian State Emergency Services	Melbourne, VIC, AU
EMERGENCY FIRST RESPONDER	2017–2018
La Trobe University Mathematics and Statistics Society	Melbourne, VIC, AU
Vice President Newsletter Editor	2016-2016
In2Science Mentor Mathematics School Outreach	Melbourne, VIC, AU 2015–2015
MENTON MATTEMATICS SCHOOL OUTREACH	2013 2013
Awards	
Vice Chancellor's Sessional Teaching Award	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University, NA	2020
Three Minute Thesis People's Choice	Saint Lucia, QLD, AU
THE UNIVERSITY OF QUEENSLAND, SCHOOL OF MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS	2020
Pitching Research Competition Best Written and Oral Pitch University-Wide	Saint Lucia, QLD, AU
The University of Queensland, Business School Pro Vice Chancellor's Commendation (awarded four times)	2019 Malhaurna VIC All
La Trobe University, University-Wide	Melbourne, VIC, AU 2018
Department Prize in Fourth Year Statistics Best Performing Student	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University, Department of Mathematics and Statistics	2018
David Myer's Medallion La Trobe's most prestigious undergraduate award	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University, College of Science, Health and Engineering	2018
Silver Scholarship Community Involvement and Dedication to Mathematics	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University Student Union, University-Wide	2017
Department Prize in Third Year Statistics Best Performing Student	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University, Department of Mathematics and Statistics	2016
Prof CJ Eliezer Prize in Second Year Mathematics Best Performing Student	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University, Department of Mathematics and Statistics	2015
Prof Jim Morrison Prize in Chemistry Best Performing Student (awarded twice) La Trobe University, School of Molecular Sciences	Melbourne, VIC, AU 2014
La Trobe Award in Community Engagement Volunteer Efforts	Melbourne, VIC, AU
La Trobe University, University-Wide	2014
Dublications	
Publications	
Pipeline	
D Fryer, H Nguyen, P Castellazzi	arXiv
K-MEANS ON POSITIVE DEFINITE MATRICES, AND AN APPLICATION TO CLUSTERING IN RADAR IMAGE SEQUENCES	2020
D Fryer, I Strümke, H Nguyen	arXiv
EXPLAINING THE DATA OR EXPLAINING A MODEL? SHAPLEY VALUES THAT UNCOVER NON-LINEAR DEPENDENCIES	2020
M Terrett, D Fryer, T Doody, H Nguyen, P Castellazzi	arXiv
SARGDV: Efficient identification of groundwater-dependent vegetation using synthetic aperture radar	2020
HD Nguyen, DV Fryer	arXiv
A BINARY-RESPONSE REGRESSION MODEL BASED ON SUPPORT VECTOR MACHINES	2020

Published

D Fryer, M Li, A Olenko

RCOSMO: R PACKAGE FOR ANALYSIS OF SPHERICAL, HEALPIX AND COSMOLOGICAL DATA

2020

D Fryer, M Li, A Olenko

Astrophysics Source Code Library,

RCOSMO: COSMIC MICROWAVE BACKGROUND DATA ANALYSIS

D Fryer, I Strümke, H Nguyen

Frontiers in Applied Mathematics

and Statistics

Research School on Statistics and

D Fryer, A Olenko

Bata ocienie

ascl:

2020

2020

2018

2017

2017

Spherical Data Handling and Analysis with R package RCOSMO 2019

D Fryer, H Nguyen, P Orban Journal of Open Source Software

STUDENTLIFE: TIDY HANDLING AND NAVIGATION OF A VALUABLE MOBILE-HEALTH DATASET

SHAPLEY VALUE CONFIDENCE INTERVALS FOR ATTRIBUTING VARIANCE EXPLAINED

Presentations and events

Building the Melbourne research student community

Statistical Society of Australia Melbourne

EARLY CAREER INDUSTRY SHOWCASE, CHIEF EVENT ORGANISER

• 6 panelists, 180 attendees https://vimeo.com/ssavic/20200922-showcase

Victorian Research Students Meeting in Probability and Statistics

Melbourne

EXPLAINING, EXPLORING AND CLUSTERING WITH NON-LINEAR AND COMPLEX DATA

UQ Research Video Pitch St Lucia

FORECASTING PSYCHIATRIC SYMPTOMS WITH DIGITAL PHENOTYPING

• First prize. youtu.be/h-m8QwLq29Y

UQ Three Minute Thesis Presentation St Lucia

Machine Learning: The Big Black Box

• People's choice award. vimeo.com/434959101

RSSDS2019 Poster Presentation Melbourne

Spherical Data Handling and Analysis with R package rcosmo 2019

• Poster and Springer book chapter

UseR!2018 Conference Brisbane

Cosmic Microwave Background data analysis with R

• R package published on CRAN. https://youtu.be/7KBsguOlEHs

Australian Mathematical Sciences Institute Summer Research School Melbourne

FUNCTIONALS OF LONG-RANGE DEPENDENT FIELDS AND HERMITE DISTRIBUTIONS

Summer Research Scholarship recipient. vrs.amsi.org.au/daniel-vidali-fryer-2017/

UNSW Statistical Challenges in Astronomy Sydney

LIGHTING TALK: A NEW R PACKAGE FOR COSMOLOGY

Fostering new collaborations in statistics and astronomy